Fairfield Families Collection Ms 37
Fairfield Museum and History Center
- Rumsey Family Papers, 1771-1790; Box IV-Folder K; 7 items
  - Writ, Ephraim Rumsey vs. Elijah Abel, 1790
  - Note from Daniel Sherwood to David Rumsey, 1776
- Scofield Family Papers, 1802-1803; Box III-Folder N; 2 items
  - Deed from Eunice Holburton to Mary and Jessie Scofield, 1802
  - Deed from Eunice Holburton to Jesse Scofield, 1803
- Sheffield, Paschal Papers, Box VII-Folder I; 4 items
  - Letters to F. D. Perry from Paschal Sheffield re: bank and insurance papers on his house, 104 Old South Rd., Southport, March, June and July 1858
- Shelton Family Papers, 1811-1930; Box III-Folder O-X; 3 folders
  William Shelton (1798-1883) was the son of Philo Shelton (1785-1825), minister of Fairfield. Sarah Bradley Shelton (1818-1863) was the daughter of Hull Bradley.
  Sarah Shelton's diary was the gift of Rodney Merwin. Items in Folder X were donated by Alice B. Colonna and are from accession number L90.Sep.7.
  - Diary and scrapbook of Sarah Shelton, 1837-1863; Folder O; Contains genealogy of the Bradley family and notes on birth, marriages and deaths.
  - Papers, Folder W
    - Letter of condolence to Mrs. Philo Shelton, 1825
    - Sermon by William Shelton, 1859
  - Papers, Folder X
    - Letters from Philo Shelton, 1811, 1823
    - Letter to H. T. Shelton, Jr., 1886
    - Frances Isham Shelton passports and wedding book, 1907
    - Lease to Henry Shelton, 1930
- Sherman, David Papers, 1708-1742; Box III-Folder P; 8 items
  David Sherman (1665-1753) was born in Stratford, CT and died in Stratfield, CT.
  - Deed from Jeremiah Judson to Capt. David Sherman, 1726
  - Deed from David Sherman, Sr. to Samuel Sherwood, 1730
  - Deed from Nathaniel Sely to Capt. David Sherman, 1730
  - Deed from Samuel Wheeler to Capt. David Sherman, 1736
  - Deed from John Hall to Capt. David Sherman, 1737
  - Deed from Benjamin Bennit to Capt. David Sherman, 1738
  - Slave paper to Capt. David Sherman from John Betts, 1741
  - Military certificate to Capt. David Sherman from Gurdon Saltonstall, Governor of CT, Oversize Item C (Oversize Manuscript Box)
- Sherwood Family Papers, Box VIII-Folder AA; 4 items
  - Applications and deeds for oyster beds on the Mill River, 1867, 1883
    These documents were donated in 1998 by John Sherwood whose family has lived in Southport for generations.
- Sherwood, John Henry Papers, 1843-1867; Box VIII-Folder T-V; 3 folders
  These items were donated by David S. Huntington in October 1996 (L96.36).
  John Henry Sherwood (1825-1918), the son of Hull Sherwood and Caroline Burr, was a farmer who resided at Greenfield Hill. His brother David H. Sherwood (1829-1892) also farmed.
  John's correspondence includes a letter from P. T. Barnum concerning preparations for the upcoming agricultural fair (1 Sept. 1851). Other letters relate to farming or family news. Evidently John was active in the Fairfield County Agricultural Society--the collection includes a copy of the society's constitution; lists of committee members; statements of crops raised by Hull Sherwood and Sons, 1850, attested to by David Sherwood; essays on the benefits of agricultural societies and a report on feed crops. The genealogy notes primarily concern the Shelton family. The school records encompass a note, 1867, from Anna Godfrey to Dimon Bradley, both of Easton, concerning the end of school terms and who appears to be an attendance record.
  - Correspondence to John Sherwood, 1846-1852; Folder T
  - Fairfield County Agricultural Society records, 1843-1850; Folder U
  - Genealogy notes, school records, and voting list, n.d., 1867; Folder V
- Smedley Family Papers, 1770-1787; Box III-Folder Q; 12 items
  John Smedley (1734-1786) and Samuel Smedley (1753-1812) were brothers. Samuel Smedley was in the shipping business and also customs collection in Fairfield. See shipping papers MS 36.
  - Writ, John Smedley vs. Jabez Cable, 1770
  - Writ, John Smedley vs. William Wakeman, 1775; This writ was a gift of Pierce W. Gaines in 1974 and involves the sale of a negro boy.
  - Writ, Jonathan Smedley vs. Shubel Gorhan, 1776
  - Writ, Jonathan Smedley vs. Sarah and George Cable, 1776
  - Writ, John Smedley vs. Nehemiah Burr, 1781
  - Probate papers of John Smedley, 1787-1794; 5 items
  - Letters to Captain Samuel Smedley re: the brig Greenfield with photocopies, 1786, 1787; 2 items
- Smith, Adeline Papers, Box IX-Folder D; 1 item
  - Letter from Adeline Smith and her cousin Polly E. Wooster of Bridgewater, Conn., to Adeline’s sister Betsy Ann Smith in Great Barrington, Mass., 1836; Adeline describes what she is learning in school and her mother’s attempts to raise silk worms. Adeline and Besty Ann are probably the daughters of Slyman Smith and his wife Susan Wooster. Item was found in collections.
- Smith Family Papers, 1773-1786; Box III-Folder R; 4 items
  - Writ, Daniell Smith vs. James Goodsell, 1773
  - Writ, Daniell Smith vs. Thaddeus Sturges, 1773
  - Writ, Samuell Smith vs. Jonathan Ogden, 1774
  - Jesse Platt vs. Benjamin Smith, Jr., 1786
- Smith, Horace R. Papers, 1850-1889; Box III-Folder S; 14 items
  These items were a gift of Mrs. Arthur Warner (L1981.July.2).
  Horace Smith appears to have lived in Bridgeport and taught school at one time in Fairfield.
  - Board and rent papers to Horace Smith, Bridgeport, 1850-1857; 9 items
  - Promissory note to Levi Worden, 1860
  - Bill to David Maloney, 1889
  - Teaching bills to Weston district no. 11 school, 1845
  - Teaching bills to Banks North school district, 1847
  - Draft exemption, 1864
- Spencer, Robert Papers, 1832-1859; Box III-Folder T; 9 items
  The deeds involve land with a factory and blacksmith's shop located in Westport, CT.
  - Abstract of Robert Spencer deeds, 1832-1852
  - Deeds to Robert Spencer from Charles W. Sherman and James C. Hawley, 1852, 1859; 5 items
  - Deeds to Robert Spencer from Elizabeth Henshaw, 1852; 2 items
- Squier Family Papers, 1770-1814; Box III-Folder U; 5 items
  - Writ, John Squier vs. Stephen Guyer, 1770
  - Writ, Samuel Squier vs. Seth Gilbert, 1773
  - Deed from Nathaniel Squier's estate to David Andres, 1784
  - Deed from Nathan Beers, Jr. to Aaron and Eunice Squier, 1812
  - Deed from Jabez and Mary Squier to Joseph Wakeman Davis, 1814
  - State Treasury bill to Samuel Squier, 1784
- Szymanski Family Papers, 1918-1940; Box VIII-Folder A
  - Brigeport City Trust Bank book of Joseph M. Szymanski, 1939-1940
  - Account solicitation from the Fairfield Trust Co., 1921
  - Baby's record of Joseph Martin Szymanski--Fairfield Trust Company
  - Building permit for Martin Szymanski for glass porch, 1933
  - Receipt from United Illuminating, 1925
  - Fairfield Trust Company bank book of Jospeh Szymanski order of Branistowa Szymanski, 1923-1933
  - People's Savings Bank bank book of Martin Szymanski or Bridget Szymanski, 1918-1937
- Taintor Family Papers, 1764-1896; Box VII-Folder C; 4 items
  These papers were donated by George Biggs of Southport (L91.Ju.12). His stepfather was Charles M. Taintor of Southport who was grandson of William Webb Wakeman of Southport.
  - Deed from Joseph Fox (New London) to Nathan Scovele (Colchester), 1764
  - Lease from Samuel Mather (Lyme) to Gideon Beebe (Lyme), 1798
  - Charles Taintor's list (with genealogy note), 1798
  - Letter to Charles M. Taintor from Charles M. Taintor, 1896
- Taylor Family Papers, 1785-1851; Box III-Folder V; 4 items
  - Samuel Taylor's account against Samuel Taylor, Jr., 1785
  - Letter from Charles Taylor to Rhoda Gray, 1828
  - Letter from Charles Taylor (Shelby, OH) to "brothers and sisters", 1851
  - Account book of Samuel Taylor, 1798-1832
- Taylor, Mary Darlington Papers, Box VII-Folders E-G
  Mary Darlington Taylor wrote for the Bridgeport Post in the 1930's and 40's. She was also curator of the Fairfield Historical Society in the 1940's.
  - Newspapers clippings and articles re: genealogy of the Taylor and Darlington families
- Tomlinson, Gideon Papers, 1780-1854; Box IV-Folder A
  Gideon Tomlinson was born in Stratford, Conn. in 1780. He attended Yale, class of 1802. In 1807 he married Sarah Bradley of Greenfield Hill, where the couple settled. Tomlinson practiced law and held public office, including the U.S. Senate and Governor of the State of Connecticut.
  This collection is made up of a few donations. L83.May.2, L82.Feb.2 (Pequot Library), L96.Jan.3 (Bob Walter).
  See Ms 33 for Clarina Brewster's will and Yale Biographies and Annals, 1792-1805 for a biography of Gideon Tomlinson.
  - Deeds, 1829-1844
  - Outgoing correspondence, 1822-1830
  - Legal papers concerning the estate of Clarina Brewster, 1843-1849
  - Probate records, 1881, n.d.
  - Receipt, 1807
  - Letter to Sarah Tomlinson (Gideon's first wife) from her sister Marion Read, 1836
- Tracy Family Papers, Box VII-Folder K
  The family lines include members of the Collins, Parry, Bulkley and Brand families.
  - Handwritten family genealogy, ca. 1895
- Treadwell Family Papers, Box IX-Folder E; 1 item
  - Form letter sent by George H. Treadwell of Albany requesting information on the Treadwell family and providing some genealogy
    Item found in collections.
- Trubee, Ansel Papers, Box IV-Folder B; 2 items
  Gift of Miss Deborah Glover, 1966.
  Ansel Trubee (1747-1823) was the son of Andres Trubee who came from Holland to Fairfield in the late 1600's.
  - Ansel Trubee's will, 1824
  - Mary C. Trubee's will, 1930
- Upshaw, Willie Papers, Box IV-Folder C; 7 items
  - Autograph and newspaper clipping of his career as a baseball player for the Toronto Blue Jays, 1985; 2 items
  - Memorabilia from Japan baseball tour, 5 items
- Wakeman, Joseph Papers, 1976-1985; Box VIII-Folder Z
  These materials were found in the Library’s vertical file.
  - Letters concerning Fairfield High School class of 1914
  - Photograph, 1976
  - Reminiscence of Fairfield in 1904
  - Memorandum, 1985
  - Newspaper clipping, 1976
- Wales, Isabelle Guibert Papers, Box VII-Folder M; 80 items
  Isabelle Guibert Wales, daughter of the rector of Trinity Church Rev. Edmund Guibert, wrote her memoirs of her life in Southport between 1890-1908 in her 80's. They were entitled "Southport Scraps."
  - Letters to George Pratt
  - Handwritten reminiscences, 1890-1908
  - Typescript of reminiscences (Southport Scraps)
  - Letter to the editor of New Yorker (describes Miss Malvina's 1856 bathing suit)
- Webb, Reverend Joseph Papers, 1693-1700; Box IV-Folder D; 1 item
  The Rev. Joseph Webb (166-1732) was minister of the Congregational Church in Fairfield in 1700 and one of the founders of Yale College.
  The sermon and memoranda were presented to Mrs. Elizabeth Gould by the Rev. Wm. A. Johnson of Salisbury, CT in 1879.
  - Sermon and diary
- Welch, Elijah Papers, Box IX-Folder G; 1 item
  Walsh was from Walkill, Orange County, New York. His will was found in the collections.
  - Will, 1818
- Welles, "Dot" Papers, Box VIII-Folder H; 1 item
  - Letter to Eleanor, (made from words and phrases cut from newspapers and magazines), 1922
- Wilson (Willson) Family Papers, 1739-1918; 40 items
  The Wilsons were early Fairfield settlers.
  - Box IV-Folder E
    - Deed, from Nathan Jennings to Robert Wilson (photograph), 1739
    - Deed, from Henry Caner to Robert Wilson, 1741
    - Deed, from Nathaniel Seley to Robert Wilson (photograph), 1747
    - Deed, from Nathaniel Wilson to Robert Wilson (photograph), 1750
    - Deed, from Elnathan Hall to Robert Wilson, 1750
    - Deed, from Andrew and Rebecca Cable to Robert Wilson, 1755
    - Deed, from John Jennings to Robert Wilson, 1758
    - Deed, from Stephen Adams to Robert Wilson, 1763, 1765
    - Deed, from Rebecca Cable to Robert Wilson, 1766
    - Deed, from Ezra Wheeler to James Wilson, 1767
    - Deed, from Gilbert and Polly Hyatt to William Wilson, 1825
    - Military certificate to James B. Wilson, 1825
    - John Wilson (Wilton) probate papers, 1808; 2 items
    - Amons Wilson (1764-1818) probate papers (photograph), 1817; 9 items
    - Henry Wilson probate papers, 1854
    - Philo Beers probate papers, 1864; 2 items
      This item is from accession number L82.Feb.2.
    - Writ, John Wilson, Jr. vs. Walter Hubbel, 1774
    - Appeal of John L. Wilson on list, 1828
    - Family records (photograph), 1821; 3 items
    - Bible records of Isaac Banks Nichols (transcribed), n.d.
    - Estate papers of Amos Wilson, 1918; 3 items
  - Box VIII-Folder C
    These items were a gift of Thomas Pearson 23 March 1999.
    - Deeds, 1797-1837
    - Deed for factory in Waterbury, 1818
- Willson, Eleazer Papers, Box IV-Folder F; 1 item; This account book covers a farm, store and weaving accounts for Eleazer Willson (1792-1857) and was a gift of Clifford E. Nichols.
  - Account book with genealogy, 1820
- Wilson, Thurza Nichols Papers, Box IV-Folder G; 1 item
  Thurza Nichols Wilson (1826-1917) married Robert Wilson in 1851.
  - Diary, partially transcribed
- Winton, Peter and Joseph Papers, 1781-1818; Box IV-Folder H; 12 items
  - Deed, from Zalmon Bradley to Peter Winton, 1810
  - Deed, from Abraham D. Baldwin to Peter Winton, 1816
  - Deed, from Hezekiah Bradley to Peter Winton, 1818
  - Writ, Joseph Winton vs. Samuel Smith, 1781
  - Bills and bills receipted to Peter Winton, 1806-1807; 5 items
  - Notes from Peter Winton, 1810, 1818; 2 items
  - Letter from Frank Fairchild Warren to Mrs. Taylor, n.d.
- Worden Family Papers, 1835-1877; Box VIII
  Worden (Wordin) family members were prominent businessmen in Bridgeport, Conn. William Wordin, Jr. married Dorcas Cook, explaining the genealogical notes on the Cooks. The materials in Folder S do not appear to be related to the Worden or Cook families. For more information on the Wordens see Orcutt’s History of Stratford and Bridgeport, Connecticut, vol. 2, pp. 925-930.
  This collection was donated by W. Bradley Morehouse in September 1996 (L96.30).
  - Correspondence of Oliver Norton Worden, 1877; Folder O
  - Worden family genealogical notes, n.d.; Folder P
  - Cook family genealogical notes, 1855, n.d.; Folder Q
  - Sales agreement, Ship Harvest, to Nathaniel S. Worden, 1844; Folder R
  - Letters from Mumford, 1820, and Wheeler, 1835; essay by Joseph Varnum, Yale 1835; poems, n.d., Folder S
- Wordin Family Papers, 1784-1860; Box IV; 15 items
  The Wordins in this collection first settled in Stratford, CT. Samuel (1760-1833) and William (1760-1814) were sons of William (1734-1808). Thomas C. Wordin (1787-1852) son of William Wordin, Jr., lived in Bridgeport.
  - Folder I
    - Deed, from Joseph Strong to Samuel Wordin (Stratfield), 1784
    - Deed, from Joseph Hawley to Samuel Wordin (Stratfield), 1800
    - Deed, from William Wordin (Stratfield) to Samuel Wordin (Stratfield)
    - Deed, from William Wordin to Samuel Wordin (Fairfield), 1808
    - Deed, from Sterling Sherman (executor) to William Wordin (Stratford), 1811
    - Deed, from William Wordin (Stratford) to Thomas Brothwell, 1814
    - Deed, from Dorcas Wordin (Stratford) to Samuel Wordin (Fairfield), 1817
    - Deed, from Grace Waklee to Samuel Wordin (Fairfield), 1818
    - Deed, from Samuel Wordin to Samuel W. Wordin, 1827
    - Deed, from Thomas Wordin (Bridgeport) to Samuel W. Wordin, 1830
    - Deed, from Sally Walker to Samuel W. Wordin, 1834
    - Grace Wakelee probate papers, 1827
    - Charles L. Wakelee probate papers, 1828
    - Thomas Wordin probate papers, 1860
  - Folder J
    - Samuel Wordin's account book, 1805-1807